1)Get First_Name from employee table using alias name “Employee Name”.

SELECT FIRST_NAME "EMPLOYEE NAME" FROM employee;

2)Get FIRST_NAME, Joining year, Joining Month and Joining Date from employee
table

SELECT FIRST_NAME, date_format(JOINING_DATE, '%Y') as year,date_format(JOINING_DATE, '%m') as month,date_format(JOINING_DATE, '%d') as date FROM EMPLOYEE;

3) Get all employee details from the employee table order by First Name Ascending
And Salary descending? 

SELECT * FROM `EMPLOYEE` ORDER by FIRST_NAME ASC, SALARY DESC;

4)Get employee details from employee table whose first name contains „o‟

SELECT * FROM `EMPLOYEE` WHERE `FIRST_NAME` LIKE '%O%';

5)Get employee details from employee table whose joining month is “January”.

SELECT * FROM `EMPLOYEE` WHERE JOINING_DATE="01";

6)Get department, total salary with respect to a department from employee table
Order By total salary descending. 

SELECT DEPARTMENT,SUM(SALARY) TOTAL_SALARY FROM EMPLOYEE GROUP BY DEPARTMENT ORDER BY TOTAL_SALARY DESC;

7)Get department wise maximum salary from employee table order by salary
ascending?

SELECT DEPARTMENT,SUM(SALARY) TOTAL_SALARY FROM EMPLOYEE GROUP BY DEPARTMENT ORDER BY TOTAL_SALARY ASC;


8)Select first_name, incentive amount from employee and incentives table for those
Employees who have incentives and incentive amount greater than 3000 

SELECT FIRST_NAME,INSENSITIVE_AMT 
FROM employee A INNER JOIN incentives B 
  ON A.EM_ID=B.EMPLOYEE_REF_ID 
AND INSENSITIVE_AMT >3000;

9)Select 2nd Highest salary from employee table

select *from employee 
group by salary 
order by  salary desc limit 1,1;

10)Select first_name, incentive amount from employee and incentives table for all
Employees who got incentives using left join.


SELECT FIRST_NAME,(INSENSITIVE_AMT)
FROM EMPLOYEE A LEFT JOIN INCENTIVES B
  ON A.EM_ID=B.EMPLOYEE_REF_ID;

11)Create View OF Employee table in which store first name, last name and salary
only.

CREATE VIEW employee_view AS SELECT FIRST_NAME,LAST_NAME,SALARY FROM employee;

12)Create Procedure to find out department wise highest salary

SELECT EM_ID,FIRST_NAME,LAST_NAME,DEPARTMENT, MAX( `SALARY`) AS SALARY FROM `EMPLOYEE` GROUP BY DEPARTMENT;


13)Create after Insert trigger on Employee table which insert records in view table. 

